After World War II, Hitler’s deadliest lieutenant escaped.
Operation Finale is a drama, history, thriller film directed by Chris Weitz.
In 1960, a team of Israeli secret agents is deployed to find Adolf Eichmann, the infamous Nazi architect
of the Holocaust, supposedly hidden in Argentina, and get him to Israel to be judged.
Peter Malkin, played by Oscar Isaac.
Adolf Eichmann, played by Ben Kingsley.
Hanna Elian, played by Mélanie Laurent.
Lothar Hermann, played by Peter Strauss.
Rafi Eitan, played by Nick Kroll.
Isser Harel, played by Lior Raz.
Operation Finale is a 2018 American historical drama thriller film directed by Chris Weitz from a screenplay by Matthew Orton about a 1960 clandestine operation
by Israeli commandos to capture former SS officer Adolf Eichmann, and transport him to Jerusalem for trial on charges of crimes against humanity.
The film stars Oscar Isaac (who also produced) as the Mossad officer Peter Malkin, and Ben Kingsley
as Eichmann, with Lior Raz, Mélanie Laurent, Nick Kroll, and Haley Lu Richardson.
Several source materials, including Eichmann in My Hands, by Peter
Malkin and Harry Stein, provided the basis for the story.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on August 29, 2018, by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer through their joint
venture with Annapurna Pictures (now called United Artists Releasing) and received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of israel, mossad, nazi, world war ii, biography.
The tone is emotional and intense.